Anton Valinov

Milwaukee, Wisconsin 53209

(414) 865-8289 • foboss2012@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/anton-valinov

Fully Work Authorized. No Visa Sponsorship Required

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

6 months experience in manual Quality Assurance engineering; 8.5 years in Geographic Information System data analysis, cartography, geocoding, map operations, and quality control; 2 years in Software/hardware consulting; 1 year in Content management. Proficient in mentoring and managing employee teams.

KEY SKILLS

- Test design, Checklists, Test cases, Bug reports, Web architecture (basic), API (json, xml);
- HTML, CSS, MySQL, Postman (basic), Visual Studio Code;
- GIS Data analysis, Map digitizing:
- Quantum GIS, HERE Map creator, Google maps, Bing maps, ArcGis, Jira, Confluence;
- Tech Lead, Task Assignment, Mentoring/Training;
- Strong knowledge in software/hardware/OS installing/maintaining/updating;
- Related skills: Microsoft Visio, Autodesk 3dsMax, Adobe Photoshop, MS Office;

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior GIS specialist, contractor (remote)

08/2013 - 12/2021

Intetics Inc., Naples, Florida, U.S.

- Analyzed and transferred data to a database of 35 countries over the world into cartographic maps software for "HERE Technologies" company;
- Digitized, entered, and maintained data from 16 different sources, such as space satellites, 360° street view car cameras, drones with lidars, systems with automatic detection of road signs, etc.;
- Took an active part in starting, supporting, developing, and successfully ending 23 different mapping projects with high final results for the customers;
- Performed Quality Assurance of documents, software, and results of the work of 42 employees, applied SQL checks, and created bug reports in the Jira tracking system;
- Communicated with customers from different countries and corresponded with the support team in 3 languages (English, Ukrainian, Russian);
- Participated in the technical lead and task assignment roles on 6 projects with a total of 15 to 28 employees;
- Created, maintained, and updated a Confluence page with important project information and modifications;
- Conducted three two-weeks training sessions for groups of 10 to 15 new employees and mentored 12 newcomers.

Software/hardware consulting manager

ProstoPlay, Kharkiv, Ukraine

raine

Consulted 40+ clients per day about software/PC hardware and entertainment/video game products;
Supported installing/setting up and performance of software/video games in 2,500+ products assortment;

Content Manager

06/2009 - 07/2010

06/2011 - 03/2013

Private enterprise «Chozyanin», Kharkiv, Ukraine

• Maintained content on the official website of the company (analyzing, editing, updating, filling);

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Volunteer

11/2022 - Present

Laboratory Assistant, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Setting up, keeping in order, unpacking, and disposing of laboratory electronic devices and models;

EDUCATION

A-Level Ukraine «QA Manual», Kharkiv, Ukraine

11/2021 - 02/2022

Specialty: manual Quality Assurance engineer. Degree: Certificate "Software testing"

Kharkiv National University of Radioelectronics, Kharkiv, Ukraine

09/2005 - 07/2008

Specialty: radio, television, and digital communication engineer. Degree: Master of Technology.

Kharkiv Radio Engineering College, Kharkiv, Ukraine

09/2001 - 07/2005

Specialty: radio technician. Degree: Bachelor.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.